# Teodor Fratiloiu

## teodor.fratiloiu@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/teodor-fratiloiu

Recent graduate of the Technical University of Munich with a MS degree in Electrical Engineering. Specialized in machine learning, cybersecurity and embedded systems, with a strong interest in the intersection of these fields. During my studies, I gained 2 years of work experience in a hypergrowth environment (5x team-level, 3x company growth) at Celonis, Germany's and New York's highest valued startup. Furthermore, I have lab and thesis project experience with machine learning, including model design and data pipelines. I am looking for a full-time engineering position in ML and/or InfoSec, ideally close to product development (including embedded and hardware).

## **EXPERIENCE**

### **Junior Information Security Analyst** – *Celonis (Munich), Part-time*

Dec 2020 – Feb 2023

- Performed gap assessments to harmonize audit controls across new and existing cybersecurity frameworks; collected audit evidence to maintain continuous compliance with ISO 27001 and SOC 2.
- Helped develop and test BC (contingency) and DR plans for business units and cloud-native products after conferring with stakeholders to identify critical software, hardware, and data assets and risks.
- Assisted with developing information security policies, standard operating procedures, and corporate training material, including the management of automated phishing training for the entire organization.
- Periodically reviewed access rights to cloud systems, assessed the physical security of premises.

**Student Assistant** – Introductory Information Security Courses at TUM

May 2020 – Jan 2021

• Prepared lab topics for students, explained solutions and hosted educational videos. Assisted the rest of the teaching staff during live remote classes for students in Munich and Singapore.

**Member and Mentor** – adveisor (Technical University of Munich)

Oct 2018 – Jun 2019

 Participated in a soft-skills and personal development programme with outside, professional coaching, including multiple 3-5 day offsite training sessions. Applied the acquired knowledge by hosting 10 project management workshops during my second year of university for "mentee" freshers.

### **EDUCATION**

#### Technical University of Munich (TUM) - Graduated

M.Sc. Electrical Engineering and Information Technology

2020 - 2023

Areas of focus: Machine Learning, Information Security and Automation

Thesis title: Peeking Into the Decision-Making Process in the Human Mind via DL Models

B.Sc. Electrical Engineering and Information Technology

2017 - 2020

Thesis: Compressing ML models to fit on embedded devices (memory & compute constraints)

## SKILLS

Languages English, German, Romanian

Coding Python, C/C++, JS/Typescript, Embedded Development

Frameworks TensorFlow, Keras, OpenCV, React, Node.js, Docker, Git, Linux

Security ISO 27001, SOC 2, NIST, OWASP